A Guide to the Mary M. Kritz papers FA269
Rockefeller Archive Center
Mary M. Kritz papers
1976-1988
Rockefeller Archive Center
Mary M. Kritz
FA269
8.4 Cubic Feet 7 standard record storage boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The files were received by the Rockefeller Archive Center, from Mary M. Kritz, in 2000 and were officially ingeted as Accession 2000:039.
Mary M. Kritz
- Correspondence 1978 & 1979-1982 A-R, 1978-1982
  - Correspondence - A-Z, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - A, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - B, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - C, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - D, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - E, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - F, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - G, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - H, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - I, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - J, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - K, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - L, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - M, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - N, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - O, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - P, Q, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - R, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1979-1982 S-Z, Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence - S, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - T, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - U, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - V, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - W, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Corresponence - X, Y, Z, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Immigration: Miscellaneous materials, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Immigration: Conference, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Immigration: Foreign policy & Immigration Links, 1983 (Box 2)
  - RF Ethnicity Conference (Box 2)
  - Immigration - Miscellaneous Program Information (Box 2)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Conference, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1981 (Box 2)
  - RF-IR Immigration Activities, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - RF: Cornelius Conferences, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Task Force on U.S. Immigration (Box 2)
  - Immigration Task Force - Miscellaneous Material, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - Immigration Task Force - Miscellaneous Material, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - MMK Diaries on Immigration (Box 2)
- Memos and reports on several immigration conferences organized by M.Kritz in the late 1970's and the 1980's
  - DeWind Diaries: Migration (Box 3)
  - RF: Immigration Activities - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Various Mailing Lists on International Migration (Box 3)
  - Aspira (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation: Immigration (Box 3)
  - Intergovernmental Committee on Migration (Box 3)
  - National Forum on Immigration and Refugee Policy (Box 3)
  - New York University Inter-American Migration Program (Box 3)
  - RF-FF Fert./Mortality Proposal: Kathleen Ford, et. al., Second Round, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Organization of American States (OAS) (Box 3)
  - U.S. Select Commission on Immigration and Refugee Policy - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan Center for Afroamerican & African Studies (Box 3)
  - Urban Institute/Rand (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, D-G, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, H-K, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, L-M, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, N-R, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, D-G, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, H-K, 1985 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1983-1988
  - Correspondence, L-M, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, N-R, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, A-G, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, L-M, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, N-R, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, A-D, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, L-O, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, P-T, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, E-K, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, U-Z, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, A-J, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, K-P, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Q-Z, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Interviews (Diaries), 1981 (Box 4)
  - Inter-office Correspondence, 1981 (Box 4)
- Diaries/Interviews, 1981-1988
  - Memos, 1982 January - June (Box 5)
  - Interviews/Diaries, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1982 July - December (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Diaries, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Diaries, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Diaries, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1987 January, February, March (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1987 April, May, June (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1987 July - December (Box 5)
  - Diaries, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Memos, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Inter-Office Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - Interviews, 1974 (Box 5)
- Diaries/Interviews 1976-1988; Correspondence 1976-1977
  - Memos, 1982 January-June (Box 6)
  - Interviews/Diaries, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1982 July-December (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Diaries, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Diaries, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Diaries, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1987 January - March (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1987 April - June (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1987 July - December (Box 6)
  - Diaries, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Memos, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Inter-office Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Interviews, 1974 (Box 6)
- Various Population Material
  - Population Council Tie-Off, 1986 (Box 7)
  - The Population Council Evaluation, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - RF Grant Review of Specific Proposals on Pop. Policy, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Population Council Miscellany (Box 7)
  - Population Council, Various Reports (Box 7)
  - US/LDC Collaboration (Hermalin) (Box 7)
  - South to South (Box 7)
  - PS Re-entry Program (Box 7)
  - Fellowship (Box 7)
  - LDC TRG Research (Box 7)
  - Saly Portudal Mtg. - Africa Initiative, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Senegal Donor Agency Meeting, 1988 (Box 7)
  - RF-FF Memos, Policy, Strategy (Box 7)
  - RF-FF Brochures (Box 7)
  - Tabulations for RF-FF Program (Box 7)